# Habib Mohamed . Jarvis Consulting

I am a University of Windsor graduate in Computer Science. I have worked in various positions as a developer working on front-end, data, and website development. I like to figure out solutions to challenging problems, and to come up with unorthodox means to implement stuff.

#### Skills

**Proficient:** Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git, HTML/CSS, Docker Competent: Python, C/C++/C#, Spring, JUnit, Flutter, PHP, JavaScript, Maven

Familiar: Subversion, Jenkins, Node.js, React.js, Eclipse

### Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_HabibMohamed

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Utilizes Liunx Bash, Postgresql, and Docker to build a monitoring agent that collects data on Linux machine specifications and performance in a cluster.

### Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: Incorporates Spring Boot, Maven, Docker, and leverages the Twitter API in order to deliver a command line interface to create, read, and delete tweets.
- JDBC App: Sets up data manipulation to a retail database using Java, Maven, Docker and Postgresql.
- Grep App: Pipelines information on a target directory for files and lines via Java 8 Streams, along with Docker and Maven, in order to find a given regular expression.

**Springboot App** [GitHub]: Demonstrates a trading system Proof of Concept for stock traders. Leverages Spring Boot, Maven, Docker, Postgresql, and the IEX API.

**Python Data Analytics** [GitHub]: Analyzes data incoming in sql files for marketing purposes using Docker, Python, Postgresql, and Jupyter Notebook.

**Hadoop** [GitHub]: To be implemented.

Spark [GitHub]: To be implemented

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: To be implemented

#### Highlighted Projects

TSVtoMySQL [GitHub]: Takes in TSV/CSV files and inserts the data into an existing MySQL database.

Department Wars [GitHub]: A small interactive React is app that plays around with the concept of Routes and Redux.

### Professional Experiences

Data Engineer, Jarvis (2020-present): Progressed through various projects and requirements using Java 8, Spring Boot, Linux, Git, Python, Docker, and other software.

Research Assistant, Department of Computer Science, University of Windsor (2019-2020): Manipulated gigabytes of data in TSV/CSV format into being inserted in MySQL databases using PHP, JavaScript, and HTML/CSS/BootStrap.

Teaching Assistant, University of Windsor (2017-2020): Administrated classes over 100 students by grading, evaluating, and tutoring on concepts such as Linux and Internet fundamentals.

Lab Manager, University of Windsor (2019): Orchestrated weekly lab sessions on game development in Unity and C#.

Youth Green Co-op Student, Progressive Software International (2018): Spearheaded the initiative to develop a mobile version of the web client. Utilized JavaScript, HTML/CSS, BootStrap and SQL to get the job done.

Web Manager, University of Windsor's Muslim Student Association (2017-2018): Directed the UWMSA's website in showcasing daily and upcoming events using Wordpress. Incorporated widgets to automate some daily tasks, seeing a boost in traffic as a result.

### Education

University of Windsor (2017-2020), Bachelor of Science (Honors), Computer Science - Graduated with distinction - Dean's List (2018-2020)

## Miscellaneous

- Reading
- Playing sports
- Cryptocurrency